There are names given
to each of the Nine Titans.
That includes the Titan you will inherit.
No matter which era this Titan
has found itself in,
it has ever pushed forward,
seeking out freedom.
For the sake of freedom, it fights.
Its name...
...the Attack Titan.
Eren was able to control
Pure Titans in the past...
...to escape a dire situation.
If someone with royal blood
is made into a Titan that I touch,
it might be possible for me to use
the Founding Titan's powers.
But if they knew of that possibility,
what would the military do to Historia?
Have a family.
Huh?
Your wife, your child,
your neighbors if need be...
Love someone inside the walls.
If you can't do that, it'll only repeat.
The same history... The same
mistakes... Over and over...
To save Mikasa, Armin, and everyone else,
you must see it through.
Mikasa? Armin? Who is that?
Who knows? I'm not sure...
Whose memories are those?
Sync and corrections by masaca
- addic7ed.com -
"The Other Side of the Wall"
Our enemy is... the world.
But if we announce this to the public,
the walls will crumble into chaos.
That's right. We still haven't fully
grasped the magnitude of this situation.
Then will we deceive the people again?
You wish to follow the lead of King Reiss
and ensure the people of the walls
stay domesticated and ignorant?
If so, then by what ideals did we rise
to take the crown from King Reiss?
Let's announce it.
After all, we're just returning
the memories King Reiss stole
back to the people a century later.
We all share the same fate
as people of the walls.
We must unite as one and
bring our entire strength together.
The true identity of the Titans
who've threatened us are humans.
They have the same ancestry as us.
We are "Subjects of Ymir."
Our King erected these
walls 100 years ago.
He then altered our memories
using Titan powers
and made us believe humanity
outside the walls was wiped out.
But in fact, humanity hasn't perished.
When speaking of Subjects of Ymir,
they call us this: A race of devils.
In the near future, the enemy will invade
our lands to obtain resources.
Their plans began five years ago
with the attack of the Colossal Titan.
I know the article's
already published,
but... Is this as credible
as you make it sound?
At the very least, it's consistent with
the doubts we've had this whole time.
I don't want to believe it,
either, but it's true.
Thanks.
So? How are people reacting?
It's a bit of everything.
Some accept it. Some laugh it off.
Some lash out at the military
and insist it's a conspiracy theory.
As all of you feared,
it's become chaotic.
Yeah, but there's no helping that.
The reports are what
put food in our mouths.
The taxpayers decide what to make of it.
That's one thing we're doing
better than the old King.
I couldn't be any prouder of all you.
Eh?
Not only as a person of the walls,
but also as a fellow working man.
Thank you.
Right... Next time, whip up an article
that pats us on the back.
What will happen to all of us?
Just as we've looked at Titans
with fear... with hate...
...and with the wish that they
would disappear from the world,
the people of the world see us not
as humans, but as dangerous monsters.
And as a result, what if this hell
only repeats itself?
Until the last of us are
wiped out, this hell...
won't end.
Hey, you heroes of the walls.
Hitch... You came?
I just came to see you
guys receive your medals.
I see.
Marlo was...
...brave all the way till the end.
Yeah.
Right, Floch? Tell her.
Sure...
Marlo Freudenberg was an
urgent recruit, just like me.
But he managed to bring
us recruits together.
The situation was hopeless and
the Scouts were on the verge of ruin.
We thought all was lost
and were stricken with fear.
But he... Only he inspired us.
Yeah?
He was an amazing person.
I know. That's why...
That's probably why he
never listened to me.
But in the end...
...I'm sure he regretted being there.
Thanks.
I'll laugh if you screw up the ceremony.
Hey! Why did you do that?
Because... Someone has to tell the truth.
I know how desperate you were
to revive Commander Erwin.
That's right.
It should have been the
commander, not you.
I'm not the only one who thinks that.
We all do.
Everyone who read the report
thinks the same thing:
Why wasn't Erwin the one picked?
What the hell do you know about Armin?
Tell me!
Nothing at all.
I'm not his childhood friend,
and we're not chums, either.
But I can still tell you
why Armin was chosen.
It's because you two and Captain Levi
brought your emotions into it.
You thought the injection was all yours
and made a totally irrational decision!
Basically, it was too hard for you
to let go of someone important.
Hey, you should shut your mouth.
Eren. Deep down inside, I bet you think
you're always in the right.
That's why you never gave up in the end.
Just like a brat that won't listen.
Eren, just leave him alone.
Mikasa's the one who
behaved like an adult.
At least she gave up in the end.
Hey! What the hell's wrong with you two?
Floch. Let's not do this during a funeral
for our fallen comrades, all right?
What's done is done,
so let's just drop it.
And you guys... You didn't
stand up to your superiors.
You didn't even stop Eren and Mikasa.
All you could do was watch.
Medals for what?
A funeral for who?
You guys better start telling the truth
when you go to enlist more recruits.
That way, you won't get cowards
like me joining by accident.
What the hell are we supposed
to do now without Erwin?!
Because... even fodder like me...
I get that I'm completely
expendable, but...
Even fodder like me...
...has a right to decide
if it's worth dying for!
Floch is right.
Commander Erwin is the
one who should've lived.
I'm not the one who can turn
this situation around.
How can you be so sure of that?
I really can't say if it was
the right decision or not.
None of us know what the future holds.
For starters, have you even
seen beyond the walls?
What is there beyond the walls?
The sea.
That's right. The sea.
You haven't seen it, right?
None of us really know anything!
Fiery water, lands of
ice, sandy snowfields!
The possibilities are endless out there!
On the other side of the
wall, freedom is...
Hey, brats.
It's time. Line up.
What did we find in the basement?
Was it hope?
Or was it despair?
Our enemy was tremendously powerful.
If nothing changes for the better,
that hideous scene will happen again.
I'd easily give up my life if it actually
managed to change something.
But I... am not about
to sacrifice Historia.
What should I do?
I can't... tell anyone...
I'm an Eldian who came
from outside the walls!
I'm a Subject of Ymir just like all you!
King of the walls!
Please, you have to kill the
Titans attacking the walls!
Before my wife... and children...!
Before the people of the walls are eaten!
Eren?
The sound of Titans being crushed
by Trost's giant sledge went silent...
...as snow began to stick.
When the piles of snow began to melt,
the military announced that Wall Maria
had been cleansed of Titans.
The elevators of Trost were dismantled,
and by the time work began
on paving the main road,
the flowers were budding
and the butterflies dancing.
Refugees were finally permitted
to return to their hometowns
roughly one year following
the attack on Trost District.
And so, six years after the
Colossal Titan's first attack...
...the Scouts once again resumed
expeditions past Wall Maria.
It's just like you thought, Hange.
The Titans inside Wall Maria
were pretty much all of them.
We thinned out the majority
in just a single year.
In that case, let's head straight
to our target as planned.
A Titan!
One showed up, huh? Be careful!
Right there...
It's not able to move?
With a body like that... it tried to
crawl to the wall, little by little?
H-Hey!
It was shipped to paradise.
It's a fellow patriot.
Let's go.
We're close.
Hey!
Is it okay to leave it here?!
Shouldn't we kill it?!
Shit!
I'm sure of it.
This is the place where Eldians
were made into Titans.
And... beyond that...
Eyy!
...My eyes!
...Damn, it's salty!
Woohoo! Is this thing
seriously all salt water?!
Huh? What's that?
Hey, Hange! It might be poisonous,
so don't touch it.
Eep!
Look!
I told you, Eren!
A salt lake so big that merchants
could spend their whole lives
and still not get all the salt.
The stuff I talked about
wasn't wrong after all!
Yeah...
It's so damn big...
Yeah.
Look, Eren!
On the other side of the wall...
There's a sea.
On the other side of the sea...
is freedom.
That's what I always believed.
But I was wrong.
On the other side of the sea...
are enemies.
Every part of this is exactly
how I saw in my dad's memories.
Hey...
If we kill all our enemies...
over there...
...will we finally... be free?